Mss.Rec.82 Mss.Rec.82
American Philosophical Society
Recordings on tape from originals given to the Library of Congress by the American Philosophical Society Library
1936, 1948-1952, 1962
Mss.Rec.82
American Philosophical Society
13.0 Reel(s)
The material in the collection is an assembly of unrelated recording collections made by multiple collectors. This collection consists of recordings on wire or phonograph discs sent by the APS Library to the Library of Congress in December 1970 in exchange for duplication of the material on to archival reel-to-reel tapes. The original formats are housed at the Library of Congress.
13 sound tape reels (18 hr., 34 min.): analog, 3 3/4 ips, 2 track, mono; 7 in.
Barlow, R. H., (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951
Conklin, Edwin Grant, 1863-1952
Croft, Kenneth
De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
Forbes, Jacques C. B.
Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
McClellan, Catharine
Parpart, Arthur Kemble, 1903-1965
Randle, Martha Champion
Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
Conditions Governing Access
Some material is this collection is restricted. Please consult a curator for details.
Frankhauser, Gerhard; Angoon (Alaska); Biology--United States; Eagle dance; Embryology -- United States.; Makah Indians--Folklore; Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole; Marriage customs and rites--Russia; Morphology.; Nahuatl Indians--Folklore; Nootka Indians--Folklore; Nootka Indians--Music; Oral histories; Papiamento; Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Songs, Papiamento; Sound recordings; Tlingit Indians--History; Tlingit Indians--Music
- Onondaga material, circa 1948; Mss.Rec.82.1; 1.0 Reel(s); Tape 1, track 1; Recorded by Fred Lukoff circa 1948. Songs and chants from the Iroquois Condolence Council ceremony. This may be a duplication of recordings made by William Fenton in 1945. (See APS Recording 1950, Mss.Rec.150.); Lukoff, Fred
  Custodial History
  Originally APS Recording 3, part 1, consisting of 13 wire spools sent to the Library of Congress for transfer to open reel tape. The tape contains only Onondaga Spool #12.
  Iroquois Indians--Music; Iroquois Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Onondaga Indians--Music; Sound recordings
  - Chants and songs of the Iroqouis Condolence Council, 1948; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:01:53; General, Alex; Lukoff, Fred; Thomas, David
    Scope and Contents note
    This recording may be a copy of recordings made on phonograph disc by William Fenton in 1945. See APS Recording 150 (Call no.: Mss.Rec.150.) Original wire recording spools were sent to the Library of Congress in 1970 in exchange for reel-to-reel copies.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Wire recording) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Cayuga Indians--Music; Iroquois Indians--Music; Iroquois Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Onondaga Indians--Music; Six Nations Indian Reserve No. 40 (Ont.)
- Cheyenne material, 1948; Mss.Rec.82.2; 5.0 Reel(s); Spans tape 1, track 2 through tape 5, track 2, part 1.; Recorded in 1948 in Lame Deer, Montana and El Reno, Oklahoma. Consists of traditional and historical stories, autobiographical narratives, unidentified texts, all given in Cheyenne only. Also includes discussions of the state of Cheyenne learning among the younger generation, and a variety of peyote, war dance, and hand game songs. Transcripts for a majority of the Cheyenne stories and texts are available in the Franz Boas Collection of Materials for American Linguistics (Call no.: Mss.497.3.B63c.); Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John, 1882-1967
  Originally APS Recording #5, consisting of 10 wire spools transferred to open reel tape for the APS by the Library of Congress in 1970.
  Cheyenne Indians--Folklore; Cheyenne Indians--History; Cheyenne Indians--Music; Cheyenne Indians--Social life and customs; Cheyenne Indians--Societies, etc.; Cheyenne language; Language attrition; Peyote songs; Sound recordings; Sun-dance
  - Text 1: Blue Elk Lodge (Cheyenne), 1948-07-03; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:46; Birdwoman, Laura; Croft, Kenneth
    Transcript available in the Franz Boas Collection of Materials for American Linguistics (Call no.: Mss.497.3.B63c.) See Related Resource. Original wire recording spools were sent to the Library of Congress in 1970 in exchange for reel-to-reel copies.
    Cheyenne Indians--Folklore; Cheyenne language; El Reno (Okla.)
  - Text 1: Blue Elk Lodge (English), 1948-07-03; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:38; Birdwoman, Laura; Croft, Kenneth
  - Text 2: Red Bird, Runaway Cheyenne Boy, 1948-07-03; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:24; Croft, Kenneth; Guerrier, William
    In Cheyenne only. A transcript of this program with English glosses is available in the Franz Boas Collection of Materials for American Linguistics (Call no.: Mss.497.3.B63c.) See Related Resource. Original wire recording spools were sent to the Library of Congress in 1970 in exchange for reel-to-reel copies.
  - Text 11: Story about a man and a woman, 1948-07-16; 01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:30; Croft, Kenneth; Guerrier, William
    In Cheyenne only. A transcript of this program with English glosses is available in the Franz Boas Collection of Materials for American Linguistics (Call no.: Mss.497.3.B63c.) See Related Resource. Transcript available in the Franz Boas Collection of Materials for American Linguistics (Call no.: Mss.497.3.B63c.) See Related Resource. Original wire recording spools were sent to the Library of Congress in 1970 in exchange for reel-to-reel copies.
  - Text 12: Story about a white man and a rabbit, 1948-07-16; 01-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:06; Croft, Kenneth; Guerrier, William
  - Text 13: Story about prairie fires, 1948-07-23; 01-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:40; Croft, Kenneth; Guerrier, William
    Cheyenne Indians; Cheyenne language; El Reno (Okla.); Grassland fires
  - Text 14: Story about white men trying to catch fish, 1948-07-23; 01-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:45; Croft, Kenneth; Guerrier, William
  - Text 15: On the selling of alcohol, 1948-07-23; 01-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:16; Croft, Kenneth; Guerrier, William
    Cheyenne Indians--Alcohol use; Cheyenne language; El Reno (Okla.)
  - Text 16: Autobiographical story about a voyage to Germany, 1948-07-13; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:04; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
    Cheyenne Indians--History; Cheyenne language; El Reno (Okla.); Germany--Description and travel
  - Text 17: Story about seven young men, 1948-07-13; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:03; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Text 18: Story about a young man who left his horse on the prairie, 1948-07-13; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:46; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Text 19: Story about an old man who went looking for his horses, 1948-07-13; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:54; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Text 20; Autobiographical story about tipis, 1948-07-13; 02-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:04; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
    Cheyenne Indians; Cheyenne language; El Reno (Okla.); Tipis
  - Text 21: Story about a white man and chief choosing a son-in-law, 1948-07-13; 02-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:53; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Text 22, 1948-07-13; 02-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:26; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
    In Cheyenne only. Original wire recording spools were sent to the Library of Congress in 1970 in exchange for reel-to-reel copies.
  - Text 25: Reminiscence of soldiers who used to interpret with the Cheyenne, 1948-07-15; 02-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:29; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
    Cheyenne Indians--Government relations; Cheyenne Indians--History; Cheyenne language; El Reno (Okla.)
  - Text 26: On forgetting old stories, 1948-07-15; 02-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:20; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
    Cheyenne Indians--Folklore; Cheyenne Indians--History; Cheyenne language; El Reno (Okla.)
  - Text 27: Story about Little Bear and Black Deer, 1948-07-15; 02-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:32; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Text 28, 1948-07-15; 02-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:54; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Text 29, 1948-07-15; 02-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:49; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Text 30, 1948-07-15; 02-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:34; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Text 31, 1948-07-15; 02-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:18; Croft, Kenneth; Guerrier, William
  - Text 32, 1948-07-15; 02-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:14; Croft, Kenneth; Guerrier, William
  - Text 23, 1948-07-15; 02-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:55; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Text 33, 1948-07-15; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:15; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Text 34, 1948-07-15; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:32; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Text 35, 1948-07-15; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:00; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Text 36, 1948-07-15; 03-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:18; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Text 37, 1948-07-15; 03-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:02; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Text 38, 1948-07-15; 03-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:06; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Unidentified Cheyenne text, 1948-07-15; 03-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:55; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Text 53: Fire-ashes and white-man-ashes (gunpowder), 1948-07; 03-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:33; Croft, Kenneth; Guerrier, William
    Cheyenne Indians--Folklore; Cheyenne language; El Reno (Okla.); Gunpowder; Tobacco
  - Text 54: When the North Cheyenne first had wagons, 1948-07; 03-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:00; Croft, Kenneth; Guerrier, William
    Cheyenne Indians--Economic conditions; Cheyenne Indians--History; Cheyenne language; El Reno (Okla.)
  - Text 55: When Bird-Woman joined the gathering, 1948-07; 03-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:51; Croft, Kenneth; Guerrier, William
  - Text 56: Story about a brother-in-law, 1948-07; 03-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:10; Croft, Kenneth; Red Bird, Charles
  - Unidentified Cheyenne song, 1948; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:06; Bigfoot, David; Blackhorse, Francis; Croft, Kenneth
    Original wire recording spools were sent to the Library of Congress in 1970 in exchange for reel-to-reel copies.
    Cheyenne Indians--Music; Cheyenne language
  - Unidentified Cheyenne song, 1948; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:39; Bigfoot, David; Blackhorse, Francis; Croft, Kenneth
  - Unidentified Cheyenne song, 1948; 04-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:26; Bigfoot, David; Blackhorse, Francis; Croft, Kenneth
  - Unidentified Cheyenne song, 1948; 04-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:57; Bigfoot, David; Blackhorse, Francis; Croft, Kenneth
  - Sun Dance Song, 1948; 04-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:17; Blackhorse, Francis; Croft, Kenneth
    Cheyenne Indians--Music; Cheyenne language; Sun-dance
  - War Dance Song, 1948; 04-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:232; Bigfoot, David; Croft, Kenneth
  - Hand Game Song, 1948; 04-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:47; Bigfoot, David; Croft, Kenneth
  - Peyote Song, 1948-06-12; 04-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:54; Croft, Kenneth; Littlebird, Harry
    Cheyenne Indians--Music; Cheyenne language; Lame Deer (Mont.); Peyote songs
  - Sun Dance Song, 1948-06-12; 04-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:44; Croft, Kenneth; Littlebird, Harry
    Cheyenne Indians--Music; Cheyenne language; Lame Deer (Mont.); Sun-dance
  - Indian Version of Star-Spangled Banner from World War II, 1948-06-12; 04-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:53; Croft, Kenneth; Littlebird, Harry
    Cheyenne Indians--Music; Cheyenne language; Lame Deer (Mont.); Star-spangled banner (Song); World War, 1939-1945--Participation, Indian
  - Peyote Song, 1948-06-12; 04-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:13; Croft, Kenneth; Littlebird, Harry
  - Sun Dance Song, 1948-06-12; 04-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:15; Croft, Kenneth; Littlebird, Harry
  - Peyote Song, 1948-06-12; 04-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:03; Croft, Kenneth; Littlebird, Harry
  - Unidentified Cheyenne song, 1948-06-12; 04-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:46; Croft, Kenneth; Littlebird, Harry
    Cheyenne Indians--Music; Cheyenne language; Lame Deer (Mont.)
  - Unidentified Cheyenne song, 1948-06-12; 04-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:36; Croft, Kenneth; Littlebird, Anna May
  - Sun Dance Song, 1948-06-12; 04-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:21; Croft, Kenneth; Littlebird, Harry
  - Sun Dance Song, 1948-06-12; 04-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:28; Croft, Kenneth; Littlebird, Anna May
  - Sun Dance Song, 1948-06-12; 04-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:43; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
  - Sun Dance Song, 1948-06-12; 04-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:59; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
  - Sun Dance Song, 1948-06-12; 04-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:23; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
  - Military Band Songs, or Chief Songs, 1948-06-12; 04-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:24; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
    Cheyenne Indians--Music; Cheyenne Indians--Societies, etc.; Cheyenne language; Lame Deer (Mont.)
  - Kit Fox Song, 1948-06-12; 04-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:28; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
  - Peyote Song, 1948-06-11; 04-28; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:19; Croft, Kenneth; Monatie, Albert
  - Crazy Dog Song, 1948-06-12; 04-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:22; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
  - Elk Society Song, 1948-06-12; 04-24; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:23; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
  - Dog Men Song, 1948-06-12; 04-25; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:47; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
  - Cheyenne Song, 1948-06-12; 04-26; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:15; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
  - Crazy Dog Song, 1948-06-12; 04-27; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:18; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
  - Peyote Song, 1948-06-11; 04-29; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:56; Croft, Kenneth; Monatie, Albert
  - Peyote Song, 1948-06-11; 04-30; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:11; Croft, Kenneth; Monatie, Albert
  - Peyote Song, 1948-06-11; 04-31; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:12; Croft, Kenneth; Monatie, Albert
  - Cheyenne War Dance Song, 1948-06-11; 04-32; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:58; Croft, Kenneth; Monatie, Albert
  - Cheyenne Round Dance Song, 1948-06-11; 04-33; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:43; Croft, Kenneth; Monatie, Albert
    Cheyenne Indians--Music; Cheyenne language; Lame Deer (Mont.); Round dancing
  - Cheyenne Hand Game Song, 1948-06-11; 04-34; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:10; Croft, Kenneth; Monatie, Albert
  - Cheyenne word list, 1948; 04-35; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:20; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
    Cheyenne language; Lame Deer (Mont.)
  - Cheyenne word and phrase elicitation, 1948; 04-36; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:23; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
  - Instruction to Children, 1948-06-09; 04-37; 1.0 .mp3; 00:18:03; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
    Cheyenne Indians--Education; Cheyenne Indians--History; Cheyenne language; Lame Deer (Mont.)
  - The Hand Game, 1948-06-09; 04-38; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:40; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
    Cheyenne Indians--Social life and customs; Cheyenne language; Lame Deer (Mont.)
  - Cheyenne Names, 1948-06-11; 04-39; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:44; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
    Cheyenne Indians; Cheyenne language; Lame Deer (Mont.); Names, Cheyenne
  - Gunpowder, 1948-06-11; 04-40; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:12; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
    Cheyenne Indians--Folklore; Cheyenne language; Gunpowder; Lame Deer (Mont.)
  - The Beginning of Civilization, 1948-06-11; 04-41; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:08; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
    Cheyenne Indians--Folklore; Cheyenne language; Lame Deer (Mont.)
  - Absent-Minded Indian, 1948-06-17; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:51; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
  - A Cheyenne War Story, 1948-06; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:50; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
    Cheyenne Indians--History; Cheyenne language; Lame Deer (Mont.)
  - Story about Big Rascal, 1948-06-17; 05-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:54; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
  - Cheyenne voice and stress contrasts, 1948-06; 05-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:57; Croft, Kenneth; Yellow Spider, Mr.
  - Cheyenne voice and stress contrasts, 1948-06; 05-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:24; Croft, Kenneth; Yellow Spider, Mr.
  - Interview with John Stands In Timber, 1948-06; 05-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:15; Croft, Kenneth; Stands In Timber, John
    Interview primarily concerns the differences in the use of the Cheyenne language among people of different generations, areas, and gender. Also discusses intermarriage between Northern and Southern Cheyenne, and intermarriage between Northern Cheyenne and other tribes. Original wire recording spools were sent to the Library of Congress in 1970 in exchange for reel-to-reel copies.
    Cheyenne Indians; Cheyenne language; Intermarriage; Lame Deer (Mont.); Language attrition
  - Interview with Harry Littlebird, 1948-06; 05-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:17; Croft, Kenneth; Littlebird, Harry
    Interview primarily concerns the differences in the use of the Cheyenne language among people of different generations, areas, and gender. Also discusses intermarriage between Northern and Southern Cheyenne, and intermarriage between Northern Cheyenne and other tribes. This program's recording levels are low, with some background noise. Original wire recording spools were sent to the Library of Congress in 1970 in exchange for reel-to-reel copies.
- Nootka and Makah stories, 1930s; Mss.Rec.82.3; 3.0 Reel(s); Spans tape 5, track 2, part 2 to tape 7, track 1, part 1; Nootka and Makah Stories, Spools #1-#5, recorded by Morris Swadesh. Includes Nootka music, group singing, historical stories, and stories in Makah. There is no collector documentation on the tapes or in manuscripts.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
  Originally APS Recording 8, consisting of 5 wire spools transferred to open reel tape for the APS by the Library of Congress in 1970.
  Makah Indians--Folklore; Makah Indians--History; Nootka Indians--Folklore; Nootka Indians--History; Nootka Indians--Music; Sound recordings
  - Nootka songs, 1949; 05-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:55; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967; Thomas, Alex; Williams, Frank
    Originally on Nootka and Makah Spool #1. Transferred to reel-to-reel tape by the Library of Congress for APS in 1970.
    Nootka Indians--Music; Port Alberni (B.C.)
  - Nootka songs, 1949; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:15; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
  - Fragment of an unidentified story in English, 1949; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:51; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Originally on Nootka and Makah Spool #2. Transferred to reel-to-reel tape by the Library of Congress for APS in 1970.
    Fiction
  - Makah stories, 1949; 06-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:57; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967; Swan, George
    Makah Indians--Folklore; Makah Indians--History; Neah Bay (Wash.)
  - Song in English with guitar, 1949; 06-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:47; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Originally on Nootka and Makah Spool #3. Transferred to reel-to-reel tape by the Library of Congress for APS in 1970.
    Guitar--Performance; Port Alberni (B.C.)
  - Christmas song, 1949; 06-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:37; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Christmas music; Nootka Indians--Music; Port Alberni (B.C.)
  - Nootka song, 1949; 06-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:20; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
  - Nootka song, 1949; 06-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:08; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
  - Nootka song, 1949; 06-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:19; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
  - Old Gallic telling about the wars which he heard about from the old people when he was a boy, 1949; 06-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:57:32; Gallic, Old; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Originally on Nootka and Makah Spool #4. Transferred to reel-to-reel tape by the Library of Congress for APS in 1970.
    Nootka Indians--History; Port Alberni (B.C.)
  - Nootka stories told by Peter Kishkish, 1949; 07-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:33; Kishkish, Peter; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Originally on Nootka and Makah Spool #5. Transferred to reel-to-reel tape by the Library of Congress for APS in 1970.
    Nootka Indians--Folklore; Nootka Indians--Music; Port Alberni (B.C.)
- Tlingit recordings made in Angoon, Alaska, 1950 June 21; Mss.Rec.82.4; 1.0 Reel(s); Spans tape 7, track 1, part 2 to tape 7, track 2, part 1; Tlingit recordings made in Angoon, Alaska, 21 June 1950, by Frederica de Laguna and Catherine McClellan. Text, "How Angoon was destroyed in 1882"; translation on typed sheets made by native from recording. Song of the Raven Hat. Three "Tsimshian" songs. The recordings were made by wire recorder loaned by Wenner-Gren Foundation; research the result of funds from the Arctic Institute of North America. This material has access restrictions. Please ask a curator for details.; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
  Originally APS Recording 15, consisting of 1 wire spool transferred to open reel tape by the Library of Congress in 1970.
  Restrictions
  There are access restrictions for this material. Please consult the Manuscripts Librarian for detail.
  Tlingit Indians--History; Tlingit Indians--Music; Tlingit language; Tsimshian Indians--Folklore
  - The history of the destruction of Angoon, 1950-06-21; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:17:05; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jones, Billy; McClellan, Catharine
    Originally APS Recording 15, recorded on wire spool, then transferred to open reel tape for the APS by the Library of Congress in 1970.
    Angoon (Alaska); Angoon (Alaska)--History; Tlingit Indians--History; Tlingit language
  - The Song of the Raven Hat, 1950-06-21; 07-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:32; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Jimmy, Mrs.; Johnson, Jimmy; Jones, Billy; McClellan, Catharine
    Angoon (Alaska); Tlingit Indians--Music
  - The Song of the Beaver Hat [1 of 2], 1950-06-22; 07-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:13; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Jimmy, Mrs.; Johnson, Jimmy; Jones, Billy; McClellan, Catharine
  - The Song of the Beaver Hat [2 of 2], 1950-06-22; 07-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:16; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Johnson, Jimmy, Mrs.; Johnson, Jimmy; Jones, Billy; McClellan, Catharine
  - Three Tsimshian songs, 1950-06-22; 07-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:33; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Elsie; Johnson, Jimmy, Mrs.; Johnson, Jimmy; Jones, Billy; McClellan, Catharine; Willis, Mary
    Angoon (Alaska); Tlingit Indians--Music; Tsimshian Indians--Music
- Yaqui Texts, January 1954; Mss.Rec.82.5; 1.0 Reel(s); Tape 7, track 2, part 2; Yaqui songs, stories, and historical narrative. Recorded by John Alden Mason in January 1954 in Marmosillo, Sonora, Mexico.; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  Originally recorded on 1 spool of wire, transferred to open reel tape for the APS by the Library of Congress in 1970.
  Sound recordings; Yaqui Indians--Folklore; Yaqui Indians--History; Yaqui Indians--Music
  - The story of coyote (Yaqui), 1954-01-07; 07-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:43; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967; Moris, Juana
    Coyote--Folklore; Hermosillo (Mexico); Yaqui Indians--Folklore
  - The story of coyote (Spanish), 1954-01-07; 07-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:10; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967; Valencia, Miguel
  - The story of the deer (Yaqui), 1954-01-07; 07-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:48; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967; Valencia, Miguel
    Hermosillo (Mexico); Yaqui Indians--Folklore
  - The story of the deer (Spanish), 1954-01-07; 07-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:11; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967; Valencia, Miguel
  - Yaqui Song: La Paloma, 1954-01-07; 07-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:16; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967; Valencia, Miguel
    Hermosillo (Mexico); Yaqui Indians--Music
  - Yaqui Song: Maria Carmela, 1954-01-07; 07-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:54; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967; Valencia, Miguel
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
  - Yaqui song about a tree, 1954-01-09; 07-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:02; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967; Valencia, Miguel
  - An account of the life and history of the Yaqui (Yaqui), 1954-01-09; 07-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:59; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967; Valencia, Miguel
    Hermosillo (Mexico); Yaqui Indians--History
  - An account of the life and history of the Yaqui (Spanish), 1954-01-09; 07-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:12; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967; Valencia, Miguel
  - Yaqui song about the deer, 1954-01-09; 07-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:55; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967; Valencia, Miguel